OMAR SAMMAN

Junior Full-Stack Software Developer

https://sammanomar.github.io/project11

https://github.com/sammanomar - https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-s-3a65b2267/

Erlangen, DE / sammanomar@hotmail.com / +49 170 2671177

Executive Summary

An undergraduate full-stack software developer. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Linguistic and expert in data processing and proficient in data visualization and KPI, Specialist in BI, forecasting, operations planning and process management on a global and regional basis. Creative regional finance/sales and market analyst with over 3 years of experiences in JCI Dubai. Excellent quantitative and analytical skills with an aptitude for problem solving. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

Feb 2023 - Present	Code Institute	Dublin, Ireland (Remote)
	Diploma in Full-Stack Software Development (Accredited by the University West of Scotlar	
5 10000 1 0007		A1 6 :

Sept 2002 - Jun 2007 University of Aleppo Aleppo, Syria

Bachelor of Economics - Banking and Financial Sciences

Technical Skillset

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Version Control
HTML CSS JavaScript Python	MongoDB MySQL	Django jQuery Bootstrap	Git GitHub Heroku

Portfolio Projects/Collaborative Projects

- 1. **Project1** My Professional Portfolio in 5 Different languages. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. https://sammanomar.github.io/project11
- 2. **Project2** Puzzle Game. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. https://sammanomar.github.io/project2
- 3. **Project3** 2 Players Connect Four game. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python https://sammanomar.github.io/project3
- 4. **Project 4** Coming soon....
- 5. **Project 5** Coming soon....
- 6. Hackathon Coming soon....(14th, June 2023 19th, June 2023)

Objective

To meet my massive ambitions to optimize my knowledge & experience, put them into optimal use & place with the optimal people, acquire a new knowledge & skills, deep dive & develop them & create a new & unprecedented knowledge.

Work Experience

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022Novum Hotels Sued GmbHNight ManagerHamburg, DESep 2019 - Jun 2022Wilkon e.K.Night AuditorNuremberg, DE

- Managing and running the whole hotels' activities independently at night.
- Managing front desk, handling guests' check-ins & check-outs, handling their overnight requests & invoices.
- Processing the daily payments and preparing the daily closure reports and forecasts.

2015 - UTD Independent Freelancer DE

- Role Player and Terp with NATO and the American military (The Big Word TBW)
- Sales Executive (BAGBNB)

March 2011 - May 2014 Johnson Controls Finance Analyst Dubai, UAE

- Preparation of monthly financial reports & gaps analysis.
- Studying and analyzing sales and market transactions.
- Launching sales and marketing information system (SMIS) implementing & conducting training campaigns in M.E region.
- Designing and building interactive BI dashboards to improve decisions making.

Oct 2008 -Mar 2011 MGCC Group Accountant Sharjah, UAE

- Responsible for payable and receivable section.
- Responsible for prepayments and lubricants transactions.
- Preparation all types of journal vouchers.

Strengths

- Gather information from various sources to explore new offerings, to improve decision-making
- Persuades other in the organization without relying on status or authority
- Proactively identifies and addresses issues to avoid surprises. Visionary with a very strong forecasting skill

Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on building my 4th and 5th projects.
- Regular engagement on Slack tech forum.
- Travelling, Reading, Sports and meditation.
- Fluent English/German/Arabic. Beginner Spanish/Korean.

References available on request.